Md Omar Faruq

Software Engineer

Address: 26/A, 18 Road, C Block, Mirpur 12, Dhaka

Mobile No: 01642031736

E-mail: faruqdeveloper@gmail.com

ABOUT

In order to prove oneself as a significant apprentice and extremely strong person and in the field of computer science and engineering one has to face any challenge of such an institution. I am an iOS software engineer, with 1 year experience in creating iPhone and iPad applications. I have been programming for the last 5 years including iOS SDK, C, QT Symbian, Swift, Swift UI, Assembler and WebDevelopment

SKILS

Proficient

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Swift, SwiftUI, php, Mysql, Sql, Familiar

Java, Git, javascript, APIs integration, Figma, MVC Architecture, Relational database

EXPERIENCE

iOS Engineer Jr Consulting

MAY 2020 - PRESENT · Australia

- Built v1 fully using Swift and v2 using UIKit.
- Implemented a scalable Firebase backend with end-to-end database encryption, storage, and cloud functions.

iOS Engineer · Leotech

NOVEMBER 2019 - APRIL2020 · Kawran Bazar Dhaka

- Built fully using SwiftUI and Json, APIs.
- Developed Bangladesh landmark for a mobile app

Web Developer · Jr Consulting

MAY 2020 · Australia

- Language php (Font-End)
- Designing Development and Deployment (full work)

AWARDS

2019 Scholar · ICT Ministry

JUN 2019 · Dhaka ,Bangladesh

- Awarded a student scholarship to attend ict Ministry 2019
- Developed interactive Swift Playground using SpriteKit.
- Networked with iOS engineers and designers about the latest in iOS development and received feedback on my apps.



EDUCATION

City University · Computer Science

April 2015 - MAY 2019 · Dhaka Bangladesh

GPA 2.64 · B.Sc in Engineering

Professional work

Apps



Bangladesh Landmarks

Most recently released app built using SwiftUI and featured on the App Store with over 1,000 users.

WEB



Happycamper

Rental RV Booking core Link:https://happycamper.site/



JRConsulting

Most recently released web site built using html,css, javascript, Bootstrap,php,Mysql

Link:https://jrconsulting.io/



Daily Essentials

Most recently released web site Multi vendors Ecommerce built using Wordpress

Link: https://dailyessentials.life/



Bdgens Wordpress Ecommerce website Link: http://bdgens.com/

Portfolio

Link: http://omarfarug.me/

INTERESTS

Rubik's Cube Speedsolving, PC Building